davey.com 2019-06-11

# Privacy Policy | Davey Tree

## Statement of Commitment

Information is one of the most powerful and valuable assets in business today. The Davey Tree Expert Company promises to safeguard the information you share with us as if it were our own.

## What Information Do We Collect?

The personal information we receive from you is voluntary. The general information you provide helps us build a better website in terms of functionality and content. With your permission, we may occasionally notify you of news at Davey Tree that may be of interest to you.

The personal information that we collect in the areas like _your local office_ section directly relates to the application or task that you have asked us to perform, such as providing a service estimate request. As with the general information, we'll use what you have provided to continue to build better service and business overall.

Certain visitors to Davey Tree’s website choose to interact with Davey Tree in ways that require Davey Tree to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Davey Tree gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for a Davey Tree account to provide a username and email address. Those who engage in transactions with Davey Tree are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, Davey Tree collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Davey Tree. Davey Tree does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

Davey Tree engages in Online Behavioral Advertising (OBA) in accordance with the guidelines set forth by the Digital Advertising Alliance. Davey Tree uses anonymous cookies to track information on your browsing history on www.davey.com and third-party advertising networks, such as the Google Display Network, use the information to serve ads to you on Davey Tree’s behalf on other sites throughout the Internet. We may from time to time contract with third-party vendors to provide ads to our customers on our behalf via the Internet or to send direct mail or catalogs to customers whom we think may be interested in our products or services. In order to do so, such vendor may collect anonymous information about your visits to our website using a “cookie”. A cookie is a small piece of data that is sent to your browser or mobile device by websites, mobile apps, and advertisements that you access or use. This data is stored on your browser or mobile device and helps website and mobile apps to remember things about you to improve your experience with the website. Third-party vendors may then pool the anonymous information that they collect from our website with other sources of information, which may include your name and mailing address, for purposes of determining whether you might be interested in receiving direct mail or a catalog. If you do not wish for cookies to be placed on your computer, most web browsers permit you to prevent that from taking place. However, please keep in mind that these technologies are an important part of how the website works; removing, rejecting or limiting the use of cookies or other similar technologies might affect the availability and functionality of the website. Any browsing cookies collected do not contain personally identifiable information, nor are they linked to any personal information collected by Davey Tree. To opt-out of receiving our direct mail or catalogs, you may send us an email at [info@davey.com](mailto:info@davey.com) or call us at **800.445.8733**.

You may opt-out of NAI Members’ online behavioral advertising cookies by using the Network Advertising Initiative's (NAI's) multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>. These opt-outs are valid only for the computer and browser combination used to opt-out. Clearing cookies will remove these opt-outs since they stored in cookies. If you opt-out of NAI third-party advertising network, you will no longer receive ads based on your browsing history from that network. You may, however, continue to receive generalized online advertising.

## Security

Davey Tree has security measures in place to help protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the personally identifiable information under its control. Davey Tree employs reasonable security measures consistent with standard industry practice to help protect against public access to personally identifiable and account activity information collected on and used by Davey Tree at this webpage. When you submit sensitive information via the webpage, your information is protected both online and offline.

Wherever we collect sensitive information (such as credit card data), that information is encrypted and transmitted to us in a secure way. You can verify this by looking for a lock icon in the address bar and looking for "https" at the beginning of the address of the Web page.

While we use encryption to protect sensitive information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, billing or customer service) are granted access to personally identifiable information. The computers/servers in which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment.

## Distribution of Information in The Davey Tree Expert Company

The general and specific information that we collect will be shared in our organization to perform the activities you've asked us to do. In addition, individual data will be aggregated and analyzed to understand customer trends and requirements, so that we can continue to provide a service that is reliable, responsive and efficient.

## Third-Party Distribution of Information

Davey Tree will never sell, rent, trade or otherwise distribute your personal information to any other organization unless compelled by law or legal process. We may, however, disclose contact information to our agents for the purpose of performing services on behalf of Davey Tree. To protect our customers' privacy, we work only with companies that agree to maintain strong confidentiality protections and prohibit them from using the information we provide for any other purpose. We do not permit these companies to sell or otherwise distribute the information we give them to any other third-party.

## Links and Third Parties' Privacy Practices

This websites may contain links to other sites that are not operated by Davey Tree.  **DAVEY TREE IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR THE PRIVACY PRACTICES OR THE CONTENT OF SUCH OTHER WEBSITES**. We provide such links only as a convenience and the inclusion of a link on the site does not imply endorsement of the linked site by Davey Tree. If you provide any personally identifiable information through any such third-party website, your transaction will occur on such third party's website (and not on this site) and the personally identifiable information you provide will be collected by and controlled by the privacy policy of that third party. Davey Tree recommends that you review the privacy policy of third party websites arrived at from links on this Site.

## Choice and Consent

The more we know about you, the better our ability to serve you and provide products and services that are of real value. Our website is a voluntary information channel that is open to you at all times. You always have a choice regarding the tools that you use and the information that you provide. We don't ask questions for the sake of asking questions, but do so because it is pertinent to our ability to serve and know you better.

## How to Contact The Davey Tree Expert Company

If you feel that we are not abiding by this Privacy Policy, you should contact us immediately:

**The Davey Tree Expert Company**  
1500 N. Mantua Street  
Kent, OH 44240

800.445.8733  

### **  
EFFECTIVE DATE**

This Privacy Policy is dated May 1, 2019. We may update this Privacy Policy at any time in order to reflect changes in our data processing practices, in personal data protection laws or otherwise. For substantial changes to this Privacy Policy, we will use reasonable endeavors to provide notice thereof.
